Finding Aid for Democratic Party of Michigan records, 1932-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- State Chair, Democratic State Central Committee files
  - State Chairman (James McNeely/Morley Winograd)
    - Topical file 1972-1973
      - Think Tank, 3 folders (Box 25)
      - Unicameral legislature (Box 25)
      - United
        - Auto Workers (UAW) (Box 25)
        - Farm Workers (Box 25)
        - Political appeal 1972 (Box 25)
      - Wallace lawsuit (Box 25)
      - Youth (Box 25)
    - County correspondence file 1969-1972
      - County information, General file (Box 25)
      - Counties
        (arranged alphabetically A-Z for all of the counties in Michigan)
        - Alger-Calhoun (Box 25)
        - Cass-Midland (Box 26)
        - Missaukee-Wexford County (Box 27)
  - State Chairman (Morley Winograd)
    - Topical file 1974 (includes some earlier papers)
      - AFL-CIO (Box 28)
      - Affirmative Action (Box 28)
      - Apportionment (Box 28)
      - Association of State Democratic Chairmen (Box 28)
      - Calendars (Box 28)
      - Clippings (Box 28)
      - Congressional delegation correspondence (Box 28)
      - Democratic Appeals Committee (Box 28)
      - Democratic Clubs (Box 28)
      - Democratic State Central Committee
        - Chairman-General (Box 28)
        - Meetings (Box 28)
        - Policy Committee
          - General (Box 28)
          - Agriculture, environment and ecology (Box 28)
          - Crime and drugs (Box 28)
          - Drafting and research (Box 28)
          - Ecology, human rights, and social welfare (Box 28)
          - Education and finance (Box 28)
          - Election reform (Box 28)
          - Foreign policy (Box 28)
          - Polling (Box 28)
        - Rules and Political Reform Bylaws (Box 28)
      - Democratic National Committee
        - General (Box 28)
        - Charter Conference
          - General (Box 28)
          - Arrangements (Box 28)
          - Caucus minutes (Box 28)
          - Delegates (Box 28)
        - Michigan delegate selection plan, 2 folders (Box 28)
        - Regional Training Institutes (Box 28)
      - Detroit-General (Box 29)
      - Education Board (Box 29)
      - Educators Caucus (Box 29)
      - Eighth Congressional District study: "A Study of the Political Climate of the Eighth Congressional District of Michigan" (Box 29)
      - Election campaign: Sander Levin for Governor Campaign file 1974
        - College (Box 29)
        - Coordinators (Box 29)
        - Correspondence (Box 29)
        - Democratic Party (Box 29)
        - Election night (Box 29)
        - Get out the vote (Box 29)
        - Interest group (Box 29)
        - Issues (Box 29)
        - Kansas City conference (Box 29)
        - Levin, Carl
          - Campaign (Box 29)
          - Letters (Box 29)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
        - Office management (Box 29)
        - Organization (Box 29)
        - Press releases (Box 29)
        - Scheduling, 2 folders (Box 29)
        - Special persons meeting, pre-primary (Box 29)
        - Wallace, George C. (Box 29)
        - Women (Box 29)
      - Finance
        - General (Box 29)
        - Budgets (Box 29)
        - Campaign kick-off (Box 29)
        - Century Fund (Box 29)
        - Five Hundred Club (Box 29)
        - Fundraising (Box 29)
        - Levin debt (Box 29)
        - Reports (Box 29)
      - Jefferson-Jackson Dinner (Box 29)
      - Leadership meetings (Box 30)
      - Leadership newsletters (Box 30)
      - Legislation
        - Election reform (Box 30)
      - Mack, Joseph (correspondence from and about) (Box 30)
      - Mackinac Bridge (Box 30)
      - Membership (information and reports), 2 folders (Box 30)
      - Memoranda
        - County/district organization (Box 30)
        - Staff (Box 30)
      - Michigan Democrat, correspondence about (Box 30)
      - Michigan (state)
        - Budget (Box 30)
        - Legislature (Box 30)
      - Milliken, William G. (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 30)
      - National telethon (Box 30)
      - Nationalities (Box 30)
      - News media (Box 30)
      - Party planks (proposed) (Box 30)
      - Polls and reports (Box 30)
      - Race track auditors (Box 30)
      - Research
        - General (Box 30)
        - Bill Hamilton file (Box 30)
      - Telethon 1974 (Box 30)
      - UAW (Box 30)
      - Upper Peninsula trip (Box 30)
      - Volunteers (Box 30)
      - Voter Identification program (Box 30)
      - Women's Commission/Women's Caucus (Box 30)
      - Workshops, Seminars, Conferences, etc. (Box 30)
      - Youngblood incident (Box 30)
    - Topical file 1975
      - Bills relating to political campaigns (Box 31)
      - Common Cause (Box 31)
      - Democratic Appeals Committee (Box 31)
      - Democratic State Central Committee
        - General (Box 31)
        - Agriculture Committee (Box 31)
        - Budget (Box 31)
        - Meetings (Box 31)
        - Platform (Box 31)
        - Policy Committee (Box 31)
        - Rules and political reform (Box 31)
      - Democratic State Chairmen
        - General (Box 31)
        - All states (Box 31)
        - Time summary (Box 31)
      - District appeals
        - 14th (Box 31)
        - 15th (Box 31)
        - 16th (Box 31)
      - Education/University boards (Box 31)
      - Environment and Consumer Policy Committee (Box 31)
      - Finance
        - Budgets 1974-1975 (Box 31)
        - Century Fund (Box 31)
        - Fundraising (Box 31)
        - General (Box 31)
        - Reports (Box 31)
      - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner (Box 32)
      - Leadership
        - Legislative Coordinating Committee (Box 32)
        - Leadership Newsletters (Box 32)
        - Officers/meeting materials (Box 32)
        - Retreat (Box 32)
      - Membership
        - General (Box 32)
        - Reports (Box 32)
      - Memoranda
        - County/District organizations (Box 32)
        - Staff (Box 32)
      - Michigan Democrat (papers relating to) (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 32)
      - Nationalities (Box 32)
      - News Media (Box 32)
      - Poll material (Box 32)
      - Precinct delegate manual (Box 32)
      - Proportional voting (Box 32)
      - Republican materials (Box 32)
      - Rules interpretation (Box 32)
      - Special interest groups (Box 32)
      - United Auto Workers (UAW) (Box 32)
      - Upper Peninsula trip (Box 32)
      - Voter Identification Program (Box 32)
      - Youth (Box 32)
    - Topical file 1976
      (includes earlier carry-over files)
      - AFL-CIO (Box 32)
      - Affirmative Action (Box 32)
        (see also Democratic National Committee)
      - Association of State Democratic Chairmen
        - General (Box 32)
        - Secretary's campaign (Box 32)
      - Attorney General (Box 32)
      - Black Lake meeting (Box 32)
      - Boy's State (Box 32)
      - Calendars (Box 32)
      - Campaign files
        - General (Box 33)
        - Bulletins (Box 33)
        - Campaign Steering Committee (Box 33)
        - Carter for President (Box 33)
        - Congressional campaign (Box 33)
        - GOTV (Get Out The Vote) (Box 33)
        - House Campaign
          - General (Box 33)
          - Coordinating Committee (Box 33)
        - Legislative Campaign (Box 33)
        - Michigan presidential primary (Box 33)
        - Riegle for U.S. Senate (Box 33)
        - Supreme Court justices (Box 33)
      - Candidates
        - Candidates Presidential Forum (Box 33)
        - Wallace Action Movement (Box 33)
      - Democratic National Committee
        - Affirmative Action
          - General (Box 33)
          - As submitted (Box 33)
        - Bylaws, 2 folders (Box 33)
        - Charter (Box 33)
        - Compliance Review Commission (re Wisconsin's delegate selection process) (Box 33)
        - Delegate selection plan (Box 33)
        - Finance Council (Box 34)
        - General correspondence (Box 34)
        - Meeting materials for October 1976 (Box 34)
        - Polling analyses (Box 34)
        - Selection of National Committee members for Michigan (Box 34)
        - Target '76 (Box 34)
        - Telethon 1975 (Box 34)
        - Voter registration (Box 34)
      - Democratic National Convention
        - General (Box 34)
        - Arrangements (Box 34)
        - Committees
          - General (Box 34)
          - Credentials Committee
            - General (Box 34)
            - Second District challenge (Box 34)
          - Platform Committee (Box 34)
          - Rules Committee (Box 34)
        - Delegates
          - General (Box 34)
          - Lists/certifications of Michigan delegates (Box 34)
          - Congressional delegation correspondence (Box 34)
          - Delegation selection implementation (Box 34)
          - Delegate intent files
            - Carter, Jimmy (Box 34)
            - Humphrey, Hubert (and miscellaneous) (Box 34)
            - Udall, Stewart (Box 34)
            - Wallace, George (Box 34)
        - Housing (Box 34)
        - Pages (Box 34)
      - Democratic State Central Committee
        - General (Box 35)
        - Policy Committee
          - General (Box 35)
          - Policy statements and related materials (Box 35)
        - Presidential Party guidelines (Box 35)
        - Rules and political reform (Box 35)
        - State chairman miscellaneous (Box 35)
          includes photos
      - Economic Task Force (Box 35)
      - Educational Finance and Taxation Task Force (Box 35)
      - Ethnic Millions Political Action Committee (EMPAC) (Box 35)
      - Federal Elections Commission allocation statements (Box 35)
      - Field staff memoranda (Box 35)
      - Finance
        - Bills relating to '74 campaign (Box 35)
        - Budgets (Box 35)
        - Century Fund (Box 35)
        - Finance reports (Box 35)
        - Five Hundred Club (Box 35)
        - Fundraising (Box 35)
        - Patronage (Box 35)
      - Hart, Philip A. (Box 35)
      - House (Michigan) correspondence (Box 35)
      - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner (Box 35)
      - Leadership
        - Legislative Coordinating Committee (Box 35)
        - Officer's meetings (Box 35)
        - Mini-retreat (Box 35)
        - Retreat (Box 35)
        - Special Elections Task Force (Box 35)
      - Lottery (Box 35)
      - Membership information (Box 35)
      - Membership reports (Box 35)
      - Memoranda
        - County/district organizations (Box 35)
        - Staff (Box 35)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 35)
      - News media (Box 35)
      - Petition drive (Box 35)
      - Political reform (Box 35)
      - Progressive Democratic Caucus (Box 35)
      - Senate (Michigan)
        - Correspondence (Box 35)
        - 11th District state senatorial special election (Box 35)
      - Senate (U.S.)
        - Guidelines for candidates and related (1976 senatorial primary) (Box 35)
      - Special interests groups (Box 36)
      - Staff (Box 36)
      - State Convention 1975 (Box 36)
      - State Convention 1976
        - General (Box 36)
        - Credentials Committee (Box 36)
        - Platform Committee (Box 36)
        - Resolutions (Box 36)
        - Rules Committee (Box 36)
        - Young (Coleman) incident (Box 36)
          (failure to invite him to greet convention delegates)
      - Tax limitation amendment (Box 36)
      - United Auto Workers (Box 36)
      - Watergate (Box 36)
    - Topical file 1977
      - Association of State Democratic Chairmen (Box 36)
      - Business and Professional Committee (Box 36)
      - Citizen's Lobby (Michigan) (Box 36)
      - Constitutional Convention (Box 36)
      - Convention (Democratic State) February 1977 (Box 36)
      - Democratic National Committee
        - General (Box 36)
        - Executive Committee (Box 36)
        - Meeting files, 3 folders (Box 37)
      - Democratic State Central Committee
        - General (Box 37)
        - Policy Committee (Box 37)
        - Rules and Political Reform (Box 37)
      - Hart-Kennedy House Dedication (Box 37)
      - Inaugural (Box 37)
      - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner (Box 37)
      - Leadership
        - Leadership Newsletter (Box 37)
        - Legislative Coordinating Committee
          - General, 2 folders (Box 37)
          - Single Business Tax (Box 37)
        - Officers meetings (Box 37)
        - Retreat, 2 folders (Box 37)
        - Select Group (Box 37)
      - Membership reports (Box 37)
      - Memoranda
        - County/district organizations (Box 37)
        - Staff (Box 37)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 37)
      - News media (Box 37)
      - Personnel
        - DSCC staff (Box 37)
        - Personnel practices reports (Box 37)
      - Primary Guidelines Subcommittee (Box 37)
      - Public Service Commission (Box 37)
      - Senate Caucus (Box 37)
      - Special interests groups (Box 37)
    - Topical file 1978
      - Calendar (Box 38)
      - Carter reelection campaign (Box 38)
      - Congressional delegation (Box 38)
      - Constitutional Convention
        - Citizens for a Constitutional Convention (Box 38)
        - Strategy Committee, 2 folders (Box 38)
      - Democratic Clubs (Box 38)
      - Democratic State Central Committee
        - Meetings, 4 folders (Box 38)
        - Rules and Political Reform meetings, 3 folders (Box 38)
      - Education
        - General (Box 38)
        - Michigan State University (Box 38)
        - Wayne State University (Box 38)
      - Election 1976
        - Analysis (Box 38)
        - Polling (Box 38)
        - Results (Box 38)
      - Equal Rights Amendment (Box 38)
      - Federal Elections Commission allocation statement (Box 38)
      - Finance
        - Bills (Box 38)
        - Budgets (Box 38)
        - Finance Committee (Box 38)
        - Five Hundred Club (Box 38)
        - Fundraising (Box 38)
        - President's Club (Box 38)
        - Washington trip, April 19 (Box 38)
      - House (Michigan), special election to the 66th district house seat (Box 38)
      - HUD (Box 38)
      - Israel (Box 38)
      - Leadership
        - Leadership Newsletter (Box 38)
        - Officers' meetings (Box 38)
      - Membership reports (Box 38)
      - Michigan political reform 1976 (Box 38)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 38)
      - Mondale, Walter (Box 38)
      - New party officers (Box 38)
      - Party platform materials (Box 38)
      - Polling 1977 (Box 38)
      - Presidential primary (Box 38)
      - Riegle, Don (Box 38)
      - Senate (Michigan)
        - Committee assignments (Box 38)
        - Correspondence (Box 38)
        - Rules reform (Box 38)
        - Senate organization (Box 38)
      - Staebler, Neil (Box 38)
      - Universal voter registration bill (Box 38)
      - White House correspondence (Box 38)
    - Campaign/elections file 1970
      - Amnesty amendment (Box 39)
      - Black leadership (Box 39)
      - Campaign
        - Candidate meetings (Box 39)
        - Clearing House, Democratic National Committee (Box 39)
        - Congressional Campaign Committee (Box 39)
        - Educational campaigns, 2 folders (Box 39)
        - Fundraising (Box 39)
        - Governor's (Box 39)
        - Planning session (Box 39)
        - Republican Party (Box 39)
        - Senate race (Box 39)
        - Structure and Financing, 2 folders (Box 39)
      - Candidates
        - Congressional (Box 39)
        - Educational (Box 39)
        - Schedule (Box 39)
        - Training session (Box 39)
      - Contest Evaluation Committee (Box 39)
      - Convention Planning Committee (Box 39)
      - Crisis contributions 1969 (Box 39)
      - Democratic platform (Box 39)
      - Directory changes (for the party) (Box 39)
      - Fair Campaign Practices Committee (Box 39)
      - Finance meeting file (Box 39)
      - Get Out the Vote Committee (Box 39)
      - Governor's Debate (Box 39)
      - House Campaign (Box 39)
      - House Campaign Committee (Box 39)
      - Joint campaign finances (Box 39)
      - Legislative Liaison Committee (Box 39)
      - Miscellaneous campaign materials (Box 39)
      - O'Brien, Lawrence, visit to the state (Box 39)
      - Picnic file (Box 39)
      - Potential Candidates (Box 39)
      - Potential Democrats letters (Box 39)
      - Secretary of State Campaign (Box 39)
    - Campaign/elections file 1970
      - Southeast Asia (minority report for platform committee) (Box 39)
      - Supreme Court Campaign (Box 39)
    - Campaign/elections files 1972
      - Democratic National Convention (Box 40)
      - General election results (Box 40)
    - Campaign/elections files 1974
      - General (Box 40)
      - Budgets (Box 40)
      - Campaign Committee (Box 40)
      - Candidate listing (Box 40)
      - Cavanagh, Jerome P. (Box 40)
      - Congressional campaign
        - General (Box 40)
        - Eighth Congressional District (Box 40)
      - Delegate selection advertisements (Box 40)
      - Democratic National Committee (Box 40)
      - Democratic National Midterm Conference (Box 40)
      - Democratic Party, Conference on Democratic Party Organization and Policy (Box 40)
      - Democratic State Convention August 1974, 2 folders (Box 40)
      - Education boards (Box 40)
      - Election Day Kits (Box 40)
      - Elections
        - 5th (Box 40)
        - 21st (Senate) (Box 40)
        - 101st (House) (Box 40)
      - Gubernatorial (Box 40)
      - House (Michigan), 2 folders (Box 40)
      - Issues
        - Education and finance (Box 40)
        - Election reform and government operations subcommittee (Box 40)
        - Foreign policy (Box 40)
        - Land use, agriculture, ecology, and environment subcommittee (Box 40)
      - Judicial (Box 41)
      - Letters, mailings, etc. (Box 41)
      - Mailing lists (Box 41)
      - Membership lists (Box 41)
      - Membership information (Box 41)
      - Memoranda from Morley Winograd (Box 41)
      - Platform planks (originals) (Box 41)
      - Policy Committee
        - General (Box 41)
        - Members (Box 41)
        - Platforms (Box 41)
      - Polling (Box 41)
      - Precinct reports (Box 41)
      - Registration and GOTV (Box 41)
      - Robo mailings (Box 41)
      - Rowe, Win (Field staff representative) (Box 41)
      - Scheduling (Box 41)
      - Senate (Michigan), 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Statistical analysis (Box 41)
      - Vandermolen, Richard (field staff representative) (Box 41)
      - Workshops, 3 folders (Box 41)
    - Campaign/election files 1975
      - State Convention January 1975 (Box 41)
      - Political reform package, Common Cause (Box 41)
    - Campaign/election files 1976
      - Campaign news releases (Box 41)
      - Democratic campaign bulletin (Box 41)
      - Democratic National Convention (Box 41)
      - Democratic State Convention (Box 41)
      - GOTV (Get Out the Vote) (Box 41)
      - Tax petition drive (Box 41)
    - Campaign/election files 1976 (geographic files)
      - District files (Box 41)
        (arranged from 1st to 19th congressional districts)
      - District bylaws (Box 42)
      - County files (Box 42)
        (arranged alphabetically by name of county)
    - Policy Committee
      - General
        - 1975-1976 (Box 42)
        - 1977 (Box 42)
      - Co-chair/vice chair files (Box 42)
      - County/district chair files (Box 42)
      - State, Counties, and Cities subcommittee (Box 42)
      - Topics
        - Education (Box 42)
        - Full employment, price stability, and balance growth (Box 42)
        - Government reform and business accountability (Box 42)
        - Human rights and social welfare (Box 42)
        - International relations (Box 42)
        - National resources and environmental quality (Box 42)
  - State Chairman File-Richard Wiener (1985-1988)
    - Advertising Spots 1988 (Box 43)
    - Affinity Card 1988 (Box 43)
    - Appeals Committee 1988, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Association of State Democratic Chairmen 1985-1988
      - American Council of Young Political Leaders 1988 (Box 43)
      - ASDC-General 1985 (Box 43)
      - Correspondence 1985-1988, 4 folders (Box 43)
      - Executive Directors 1985 (Box 43)
      - Fundraising 1984 (Box 43)
      - Lunde and Burger 1988 (Box 43)
      - Summer Meeting 1987, 3 folders (Box 43)
    - Ballot Security 1988 (Box 43)
    - Budget 1988 (Box 43)
    - Bates, Richard 1988 (Box 43)
    - Blanchard, James 1988 (Box 43)
    - Campaign Finance Act 1988 (Box 43)
    - Campaign Strategy 1988 (Box 43)
    - Chamber of Commerce 1988 (Box 43)
    - Compliance Assistance Commission 1988 (Box 43)
    - Correspondence 1983-1985, 11 folders (Box 43)
    - Correspondence 1988, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Delegate Selection Documents/Affirmative Action Report 1988 (Box 44)
    - Democratic National Committee-Joint Fundraising Committee 1988 (Box 44)
    - Democratic National Convention and Campaign File 1988
      - General caucus and campaign information (Box 44)
      - Dukakis-Bentsen Campaign Materials May-December 1988, 2 folders (Box 44)
      - State Election Miscellanea 1988 (Box 44)
      - Correspondence June-November, 1988 (Box 44)
    - Dollars for Democrats 1988 (Box 44)
    - Douglas, Bruce 1988 (Box 44)
    - Eleventh Congressional District 1988 (Box 44)
    - Fax Transmittals 1988 (Box 44)
    - Federal Election Commission 1988 (Box 44)
    - Fifth Congressional District 1988 (Box 44)
    - Fox, Mark 1988 (Box 44)
    - Fundraising 1988 (Box 44)
    - Governor's Appointments 1988 (Box 44)
    - How to Handbook (Box 44)
    - Kids as Politics Revisited, Stanley Greenberg, 1988 (Box 44)
    - Medicaid 1988 (Box 44)
    - Middle East Resolution 1988 (Box 44)
    - Party Platform 1988 (Box 44)
    - Policy Reports 1988 (Box 44)
    - Pollack, Lana 1988 (Box 44)
    - Press Releases 1988 (Box 44)
    - Prospects for Victory in 1988, 1988 (Box 44)
    - Reagan Administration (Old Nazis, The New Right and the Reagan Administration), 1988 (Box 44)
    - Reapportionment 1988 (Box 44)
    - Reapportionment Meetings 1988 (Box 44)
    - Recount: Crawford-Economy-Dumouchelle-Lundy 1988 (Box 44)
    - Role of the State Democratic Party in the Senate Challenger's Campaign 1988 (Box 44)
    - Rules Committee, State Convention 1988 (Box 44)
    - Secretary of State-Driver License File 1988 (Box 44)
    - Senate Bill 349 Memos 1988 (Box 44)
    - State Journal Editorial (Democrats Prepare to Elect President), 1988 (Box 44)
    - State Party Activity Under Federal Law 1988 (Box 44)
    - Voter Database 1988 (Box 44)
  - State Chairman File-F. Thomas Lewand (1989)
    - Ahmed, Ishmael 1989 (Box 44)
    - Appeals Committee 1989, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Blanchard's State Convention Speech 1990 (Box 44)
    - Boys' State 1989 (Box 44)
    - Budget 1989
      - Current 1989 (Box 44)
      - Operating-Last 5 years 1989 (Box 44)
    - Business Forum 1989 (Box 44)
    - Byrski, Mary 1989 (Box 44)
    - Campaign '90 1989 (Box 44)
    - Campaign Finance Planning 1989 (Box 44)
    - Campaign Training Seminars 1990 (Box 44)
    - Cole, Rick 1989 (Box 44)
    - Computer System 1989 (Box 44)
    - Correspondence 1989, 8 folders (Box 44)
    - County and District Chairs 1989 (Box 44)
    - Database 1989 (Box 44)
    - Database Proposals 1989 (Box 44)
    - Democratic Leadership Council 1990 (Box 44)
    - Directions in Public Finance, Traverse City Conference 1989 (Box 44)
    - Focus on Youth 1989 (Box 44)
    - Fourth Congressional District 1989 (Box 44)
    - Gephardt, Richard 1989 (Box 44)
    - Hicks, Greg 1989 (Box 44)
    - Labor Issues 1989 (Box 44)
    - Leadership Conference November 10-11, 1991 (Box 44)
    - Leadership Correspondence 1989 (Box 44)
    - Leadership Meetings 1989 (Box 44)
    - Legislative File 1989 (Box 45)
    - Lewand, F. Thomas
      - General 1989 (Box 45)
      - Speeches 1989 (Box 45)
    - Local Elected Officials 1989 (Box 45)
    - Macomb County (Report on the Swing Electorate: Macomb County Revisited), 1989 (Box 45)
    - Macomb/Wayne Briefing Reports 1989 (Box 45)